Now that we have finished the back end of image compression, the simple coding that
通过一个例子 我们现在已经完成了基于霍夫曼编码的简单编码
we do with Hoffman coding, in the example that I presented, let's go to the front
这是图像压缩的后端步骤 接下来让我们看看图像压缩的前端
end of image compression. Basically what we're going to describe in
在这个视频中我们将要讲述的是这一部分
this video is this part. So let's just start with this component.
那么让我们从这个部分开始
What we have is an image, and the fur think that at J big dash or a
现在我们有一张图片 一个粗略的想法是 JPEG
law see transfer compression does is divides the image into blocks.
或者有损变换编解码压缩 做的是把图片分成一些小块
Each one of these blocks has n by n pixels, and we're going to talk, we're
每一个小块有 n x n 个像素点 我们要讲的是
going to give examples of what's the value of N, but just to give you an idea,
用一个例子来讲解 n 值是什么 但我们先了解一点
a JPEG uses eight by eight. So, basically, jpeg codes almost
就是 JPEG 使用的是 8 x 8 的小块
independently every eight by eight block of the image.
所以 JPEG几乎是将一幅图像中的每个 8 x 8 小块独立编码
These are non-overlapping block, so here are eight, then eight, then eight, then
小块都是不重叠的 所以这是8个像素 接着8个 接着8个
eight. Okay.
接着8个 好
And we go all the way. And there are techniques what to do if
然后全部都是这样 并且也有方法来处理
your image width is not a multiple of eight and so on.
如果图片的宽度或者长度不是8的倍数的情况
So, don't worry about that for the moment.
所以现在不用担心这个
Those are just technical details. So we take an N by N block, and we are
这些只是技术细节 我们取其中一个 n x n 的小块
going to encode each one of those N by N, eight by eight blocks.
接下来我们将要对每一个这样的 n x n  8 x 8 的小块编码
And as I say that are encoded almost independently.
并且我之前讲过 编码的时候它们几乎是独立的
Now, this is what you do with one image, but this is if you only have a black and
这就是要对一张图片做的事 但是这只是针对黑白图片
white image. What happens if I have an RGB image?
如果是一张RGB图片怎么办呢
So jpeg is what's called color blind. Jpeg doesn't know how to deal with color.
JPEG 其实是个色盲 JPEG 不知道如何处理色彩
The standard itself, but there's some assumptions that are made.
它本身不理解颜色标准 但是我们可以想一下怎么来处理这个问题
Originally what you could do is you just take the red.
最原始的一个想法是 首先把红色通道取出来
Remember every channel is a two-dimensional array of pixels.
因为每一个通道都是一个二维像素阵列
So the red looks like this. You divide the red in eight by eight
于是红色通道看起来是这样的 我们将红色通道分成 8 x 8 的小块
blocks and you code the red. You do the same with the green,
之后对红色通道编码 然后对绿色通道做同样的处理
you do the same with the blue, and that's perfectly legitimate.
最后对蓝色通道做同样的处理 看起来这个方法非常合理
Now, normally there's, basically a lot of correlation between
但是实际情况是 通道之间有很多相关性
the channels. So what basically jpeg does, instead of
所以 JPEG 做的是
calling RGB, it goes in to what's called Y.
它不对RGB编码 而是处理一种叫YCbCr的色彩空间
Cb, CR. I'm going to tell you in a second how to
接下来我就来告诉大家怎么做这个
do that. But these are, instead of three channels
但是在这里
RGB, you have three channels which are Y, CB, and CR.
我们有Y、Cb和Cr三个通道 而不是RGB三个通道
This is a luminance channel, which is basically what you will see if you have a
这个是亮度通道 (luminance channel) 这就是大家
black and white TV or a black and white monitor.
在黑白电视机和黑白显示器上见到的通道
You will get a color image, but you will only see, basically, the black and white
我们有一张彩色图片 但是只能看到黑白的部分
component, the luminous component, of it. And these are the colors.
也就是它的亮度部分 这些是色彩通道
Okay. And this is a very simple transform.
好 这是一个简单的转换
This is actually done by a three by three, matrix.
实际上是通过乘以一个 3 x 3 的矩阵来实现的
So you basically are going to have your y.
我们把Y Cb Cr列成一列
Cb, CR, as a column. You have a three by three matrix here,
这里是一个 3 x 3 的矩阵
three by three, and you have your RGB values. So the y is
这是 R G B的值
a linear combination of the rgb, the cbr is a linear combination.
所以Y是R G B的一个线性组合 Cbr也是一个线性组合
The CB a linear combination, and the CR another, and this matrix is invertible,
Cb是一个线性组合 Cr是另一个线性组合 这个矩阵是可逆的
so once you decode a YCBCR, you multiply by the inverse of this matrix and you get
所以在对YCbCr解码时 将它们乘以这个矩阵的逆矩阵
back the RGB. So the very first thing that jpeg does,
就能回到R G B值了 JPEG最开始会做的事
it takes your color image, mulitplies it by a matrix, so basically every pixel.
是将彩色图片的每一个像素乘上一个矩阵
Let's say 100, 1650, 200. You multiply by the coefficients here.
比如 100、150、200 乘上这里的这些系数
This is a constant matrix, that is given is very well known.
这是一个常数矩阵 这个矩阵非常有名
It appears all over, if you just, Google YCBCR, you're going to get the values of
它在很多地方都有出现 如果用 谷歌 (Google) 搜索 YCbCr
this matrix. So it goes over every single pixel of the
就能够知道这个矩阵的确切数值 这样对图像的每一个像素点都进行处理
image and transforms it from red, green, blue arrays into YCbCr arrays.
把红绿蓝 (RGB) 阵列转换成 YCbCr 阵列
Once again, 2-dimensional arrays where every pixel, now instead being an RGB is
我再重复一次 这仍然是所有像素点的一个二维阵列 不过已经从RGB
a YCbCr. So it has those, and then it's going to
转换成了YCbCr的二维矩阵 有了这些 接下来就是
encode each one of these arrays independently.
对其中的每一个阵列分别进行编码
So let's look at Y. It will go into Y.
让我们来看看Y通道 先处理Y通道
And it will divide it in eight by eight blocks.
将其分成 8 x 8 的小块
Okay, and that's all what's going to do. And then it's going to take each one of
好 我们要做的就是这些 接下来把每一个 8 x 8 小块取出来
these eight by eight blocks, and it's going to encode them.
将它们分别编码
As I say, almost independently, but for the sake of this presentation,
如前所述 几乎独立地编码 但是为了更好地讲解它
we're going to consider them independently.
我们将其认为是独立的
So it's going to encode a lot of eight by eight small images.
接着要将很多 8 x 8 的小图片编码
And how it's going to do that, It's going to do that with a discrete
接下来它将怎么做呢 接下来要做的是一个离散余弦变换 (DCT)
cosine transform, a transform. Then a quantization, and then what, a
一个变换 然后是量化
symbol encoding. As we have seen so many times with the
然后是符号编码 就像我们已经见过很多次的那个 JPEG 流程图表示的那样
diagram of jpeg. So now, we have an eight by eight block.
现在我们有了这个 8 x 8 的小块
And all that we need to think about now is that we have a small eight by eight
现在我们需要关注的是我们有的这些 8 x 8 的图像
image.
//果壳教育无边界字幕组 | ctzsm |  leafsherry | 小白_远游